Email-Id: rhsmca@gmail.com

Summary:

 5+ years of experience in Software Development for Java/J2EE, JSP, Servlet, Spring, Hibernate, Struts2, REST Web services, MyBatis, JUnits, SonarQube, Elasticsearch, Html, javascript, AngularJs and equivalent domain expertise in Banking, Financial Services & Insurance (BFSI).

MB: 919689294840

- Part of all the phases of Software Development Life cycle (SDLC) which includes Requirement gathering, Design, Construction, Testing, Implementation.
- Infosys Global Agile Developer certified and fully aware of best practices of industry agile methodology.

Professional Experience:

- Infosys Limited Pune, Position: Technology Analyst (Sep 2014 till Date).
- CRIF-High Mark Credit Information S. Pvt Ltd Pune, Position: Software Developer Associate (Nov 2012 to Sep 2014)
- Quimztech Solutions Pvt Ltd Pune, Position: Java Developer (Feb 2012 to Nov 2012).

Computer Proficiency:

 Languages : Core Java, J2EE, JSP, Servlet, Web services (REST/SOAP), xml. : Spring 3.x, Hibernate, Struts2.X, Maven, Log4j, MyBatis, SAX & Framework

XStream parser, SMB, Apache POI.

Development Tool (IDE) : Eclipse, Intellij, NetBean7.x, Toad, JDeveloper, Dojo, WySiwyn.

 Web Designing language : HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJs.

: SQL, Oracle 10g, MS-Sql Server, MS- Access. Database language : Agile Development, Microsoft Office 2003/07. Documentation Skill

 Operating Systems known : DOS, Windows XP Onwards.

 Other Tools : Elastic Search, SonarQube, SVN, TFS, Perforce, Team Viewer.

Professional Projects:

Application Name: TEMPO (Trade Exchange Management Portal)

Client : Barclays PLC (UK & India)

Team size

Description : It is used in Investment Banking & sales for Managing Investment banking products

As like Equity, Bonds, Foreign exchange, Option, Forward, Future etc. it calculates

brokerages & Manage Buying Center & Client, Trades, sales persons etc.

: Analyzing and designing, coding the requirement and accordingly **Role Played**

> Completing the Construction of the project by following the Infosys agile Methodology. Developed Web Services (REST) on top of Spring MVC, Preparation of all sorts of required Documents like Product Backlog, Sprint

Backlog, Sprint Burn down Chart etc.

Platform core Java, J2ee, Spring, REST Web Services, Maven, Mybaits, MS-SQL Server, HTML,

Javascript, AngularJs, SonarQube.

Application Name: Bureau Link 2.0

Client : Major MFIs and Financial Institutions.

Team size : 4

Description : Bureau Link Calls Business Services of Credit Bureau Companies like CIBIL,

Experian, Equifax & High Mark for Generate High Score Consolidated Credit Report Of Borrower for Microfinance, Consumer, Commercial Banking, Insurance, Telecom

& Other Sectors.

Role Played: Worked as a **Developer** in the coding phase for application Development. I was

Responsible for understanding program Specification & code development as per Specification. I have also worked as Maintenance role to solve the issues & bugs,

Unit Testing, Requirement gathering.

Platform : j2sdk1.6, JSP, Servlet, Struts2, Spring, Web Services.

Application Name: Credit Bureau Inquiry.

Team size : 5

Description: Generate Credit Information of Borrower for Microfinance, Consumer, Commercial

Banking, Insurance, Telecom & Other Sectors.

Role Played: Worked as a **Developer** in the coding phase for application Development, solve

Issues & Bugs, Unit Testing.

Platform : j2sdk1.6, JSP, Servlet, Struts2, spring, oracle.

Application Name: AON Insurance **Client** : AON Hewitt (US)

Team size : 3

Description: It is **Microsites project** which aims to Enrollment different insurance form &

Display all Insurance plans to US people.

Role Played: Worked as a **Developer** in the coding phase & solve the issues & bugs.

Platform : core java JSP, Servlet, Struts2, MS-SQL.

Application Name: Hospital Data Analysis.

Team size : 4

Description: Managing Electronic Health care records.

Role Played: Software Developer.

Platform : core java, JSP, Servlet, Struts2, Hibernate.

Education Qualifications:

Examination	University / Exam Body	Year of Passing	Percentage
DJVT	NIIT Pune.	2012	79.00%
MCA	Swami Ramanand Teerth Marathwada University, Nanded.	2012	69.00%
BCA	Swami Ramanand Teerth Marathwada University, Nanded.	2009	64.63 %
H.S.C	Maharashtra State Board of Secondary & Higher Secondary Education, Pune.	2006	63.50 %
ITI	Industrial Training Institute Udgir.	2004	72.71%
S.S.C	Maharashtra State Board of Secondary & Higher Secondary Education, Pune.	2003	68.93 %

Achievements:

- OCJP 1.6 (Oracle Certified Java Professional Programmer) Certification-"Oracle University US".
- Insta Awards from Infosys Ltd.
- Infosys Agile Developer Certified from Infosys Ltd.
- Highmark Got Talent 2013 (Solo Performance Winner).
- National Trade Certificate- awarded from GOVT of India (Ministry of Labor).
- National Apprenticeship Certificate awarded from GOVT of India (Ministry of Labor).

Extra-Curricular Activities:

- Attend National Conference On New Trends in Computer Science in 2010.
- Attend National Conference on Emerging Trends in Biological & Information Science in 2011.

Personal Details:

Date of Birth : JAN-01-1988.

• Father's Name : Harishchandra Shankarrao Suryawanshi.

Alternate Email id : rhsmca@gmail.com

Phone-residence : 91-9689294840 / 91-8180027410.

Nationality : Indian.Gender : Male.

• **Residential Address:** Vishal apartment Ram nagar, behind Mayur nagari, Katepuram chowk, Pimple Gurav, Pune.

Key Strength:

Comprehensive problem solving abilities, Ability to deal with people diplomatically, Hard worker, Willingness to learn from surrounding things, Leadership Ability, Great confidence, Trying to accept every challenge, self-believing, Always positive thinking.

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: / /	Yours Sincerely,
Date: / /	Yours Sincerely